# NICOLE BLAZIER

UX/UI DEVELOPER

(210) 245-1789 | nicole.blazier@mail.com | https://nicole-blazier.netlify.app/ | San Antonio, TX

#### SUMMARY

UX/UI Developer with 7+ years of experience in front-end development, specializing in **JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and React**. Integrated modern UI component libraries into legacy systems at CPS Energy, aligning with enterprise-wide UX/UI standards. At Novartis, delivered internationally compliant, user-centered designs and enhanced data privacy practices for EU PharmaLedger initiatives.

#### SKILLS

HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JavaScript | React | Angular | Vue.js | JSP | Node.js | Bootstrap | Material UI | Tailwind | REST APIs GitLab | GitHub | VS Code | Intellij | NPM | Postman | Jira | Confluence | Agile | Scrum | Figma | Adobe XD | AEM | ADA

## **EXPERIENCE**

CPS Energy: UX/UI Developer

Sept 2023 - Present

#### **AutoReconnect Project**

- Engineered modular, 14 reusable front-end components in JavaScript and Vue in legacy payment system codebase.
- Secured transmission and storage of sensitive financial data through robust 8 API integrations, ensuring data privacy.
- Integrated a scalable design language system into the legacy codebase using **Bootstrap** for 60% consistency in code.
- Collaborated debugging with back-end team, decreasing latency of two major causes of crashes on payment system.
- Resolved 20+ front-end UI bugs, improving reliability and reducing user error.

## Residential Redesigns Project

- Built UX/UI development of Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) using JavaScript, HTL, and CSS.
- Architected a highly configurable 30+ AEM components, enabling consistent layout reused across all templates.
- Enhanced digital accessibility with WCAG 2.1 guidelines ensuring inclusivity across devices and demographics.
- Streamlined user flows by reducing the number of interaction points, resulting in a 30% boost in user engagement.

Novartis: UX/UI Developer

Jan 2019 – Apr 2022

Supply Chain Blockchain Project - PharmaLedger Consortium (EU 2-billion-dollar funded)

- Led UI/UX design and development using React.js and Spherity's Blockchain APIs and OpenDSU offline storage system.
- Co-developed 10+ user-flows for PharmaLedger's patient-center application initiative to ensure design consistency.

## EPI Blockchain Project - PharmaLedger Consortium

- Spearheaded front-end development of the blockchain-enabled electronic product information (ePI) app.
- Enabled users to scan GS1 2D DataMatrix codes on packaging to instantly receive up-to-date, approved drug leaflets.

## AE Brain (AI/ML) Project

- Developed the AE Brain application using React.js and BERT NLP models to enable detection of adverse drug events.
- Achieved to a \$30M annual reduction in pharmacovigilance costs and improved medication safety outcomes.
- Established user-centric design process using Jira for a team of 4 developers, cutting project delays by 15%.

## **EDUCATION**

Masters of Business Administration | Texas A&M University – Commerce, TX Communication Studies | Louisiana State University – Baton Rouge, LA

Aug 2010 – Dec 2013

Aug 2005 - Aug 2010